# **David Williams**

## **David Williams**

Apartment 54 7 Tiltman Place London N7 7EL United Kingdom

+447432104037 dave@dave.io



Please note that I am exclusively considering 100% remote roles.

**Skills** 

Motivated, qualified, and experienced multiplatform infrastructure and DevOps engineer and team lead, specialising in Kubernetes and Linux/\*BSD cloud environments, but comfortable in Windows and on-premises or hybrid architectures.

Comfortable running, growing, and managing a team, including upskilling team members and sprint-based task and project management. Not a micromanager, preferring to trust team members, discovering and addressing any support needs in open conversation.

Experienced in rapid triage and balancing break/fix work against larger-scope project work.

Strong communicator and believer in involving as many stakeholders as possible by default, while being open to reducing verbosity as desired by each involved party if and when requested.

Extensively experienced with various cloud platforms, particularly Google Cloud Platform and Amazon Web Services.

Experienced with Linux, \*BSD, and various network appliance operating systems such as IOS, Vyatta, MikroTik, Ubiquiti, and Juniper.

Strong Kubernetes administration and troubleshooting experience, including initial builds and value-adds such as Linkerd and Prometheus.

Great believer in automation over repetitive busywork, both in terms of freeing up engineer brain-time for more complicated issues and of minimisation of possible human error.

Self-taught skills and lifelong special interest in information security, penetration testing, platform hardening, DFIR, and IoT security.

Experienced with Go, Python, Ruby, JavaScript (including TypeScript), and shellscript. Intermediate skills with Java.

Currently self-teaching frontend development with React.

Lateral and quick thinker when emergent circumstances inevitably arise.

Nonprofessional experience of electronic engineering and "making". Member of the London Hackspace since its inception.

Self-taught amateur radio licensee and owner of too many screwdrivers.

Self-taught alleged musician and owner of too many synthesisers.

**Experience** 

#### Feeld / Head of Infrastructure

OCTOBER 2019 - JUNE 2023, REMOTE

- Created and managed a dedicated infrastructure team where none previously existed
- Handled recruitment, training, project and budget management, and operated across multiple time zones
- Reported directly to C-suite to drive infrastructure strategy
- Built second-generation incident management platform and shared the on-call responsibilities
  - Implemented automated remediation to mitigate frequent issues until fixes were developed and deployed
  - Ensured all stakeholders received timely information tailored to their role, driving cross-team collaboration and informing strategic planning
- Built runbooks for key components and microservices
- Set up a single pane of glass for metrics to speed incident response and proactive maintenance
- Worked closely with developers to instrument codebase with OpenTelemetry, and implemented analysis tooling
- Created and drove a cross-team initiative to tame overly verbose logging, saving more than 50% of previous infra costs
- Built second generation Kubernetes-centric environment from scratch, including –
  - Fully managed infrastructure-as-code with Pulumi
  - o GitOps using Flux and Weave
  - o The Linkerd service mesh
  - Gloo ingress
  - Full OpenTelemetry metrics and tracing
  - A secure, low-friction SD-WAN VPN to replace the bastion system which was slowing development work
  - Migration of MongoDB, Redis, and Postgres from disparate external providers into GCP, resulting in significant cost savings and lowered request latencies
  - Serverless technologies such as Cloud Functions and event-driven containers where appropriate, reducing both complexity and costs
- Proposed and built cloud-based streaming video platform from scratch in response to COVID-19 causing public events, previously a major growth tool, to become unavailable
  - Self-taught remote livestream production skills in a very short timeframe
  - Developed tooling to allow low-latency use of local MIDI/OSC control surfaces with cloud VMs
  - Personally endorsed by growth team for single handedly creating an entirely new and highly successful acquisition stream which is still in use
  - Coordinated with non-technical guests to provide training and backchannel comms during streams

## Mozilla / MOC Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2016 - OCTOBER 2019, REMOTE

- Extremely wide-ranging remote role, demanding broad skillset and ability to learn new skills quickly
- Management of the full Mozilla infrastructure
- On-call duties
- Communication and collaboration with diverse teams, with varying foci and levels of technical competency
- Point of contact for "I don't know who I should talk to about this, but" queries
- Began development of in-house operations intelligence software ('Panopticon').

## Facebook / Production Engineer

AUGUST 2013 - JULY 2014, SAN FRANCISCO

- Working with the Facebook storage infrastructure
- Massive-scale Linux administration and toolset development
- Commissioned new datacentre location in Malmö
  - o Performed initial data seeding
  - Implemented ongoing replication
  - Integrated new resources into global multi-tier storage infrastructure
- On-call duties

## Six Degrees Group / Systems Administrator

### Previously **Ultraspeed**

AUGUST 2009 - SEPTEMBER 2013, LONDON

- Part of a small team running a large Linux and Windows managed hosting estate backed on VMware
- Hands-on datacentre work
- On-call duties
- Tierless phone support, taking calls from clients, triaging issues, and getting things fixed the right way the first time
- Face to face site visits to customer sites to demonstrate architecture and prepare for any special scaling requirements
- 3PAR SAN administration
- Vvatta network administration
- Threat management and attack surface reduction
- Design, implementation, and ongoing ownership of managed backup platform

#### ioko / Systems Administrator

JULY 2008 - JUNE 2009, LONDON AND YORK

- Worked with large-scale IPTV, including BSkyB and Channel 4
- Linux-based deployment management
- Internal toolset development
- Systems support
- Hands-on datacentre work
- Self-taught Solaris platform
- On-call duties

## **Inspired Gaming Group / Systems Administrator**

MAY 2006 - MAY 2007, LONDON

- Systems administration for a mid-scale RHEL, Windows, and AIX estate
- Managed migration of physical server estate to VMware virtualisation
- EMC SAN administration
- On-call duties

#### **DXI Networks** / VoIP Engineer

FEBRUARY 2005 - APRIL 2006, LONDON

- Design, implementation, and support of a countrywide Cisco VoIP deployment with 50+ sites
- Travel to customer sites and on-site deployment work
- On-call duties

#### Education

## **University of Kent** / Computer Science (BSc 2.2 Hons)

SEPTEMBER 2003 - JULY 2007, CANTERBURY

#### ITIL / ITIL Certified

FEBRUARY 2009

## **Red Hat** / Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHEL 5)

APRIL 2007

## **Keywords**

3PAR, Amazon Web Services, Apache, Asigra Enterprise Backup, Automation, AWS, Azure, CentOS, Cloud Computing, Containers, cPanel, Database Administration, DevOps, Docker, EMC, FreeBSD, GCP, Google Cloud Platform, HAProxy, High Availability, IT Security, ITIL, Kubernetes, Linkerd, Linux, Load Balancing, Mac OS X, MySQL, NAS, Network Administration, Network Security, Nginx, Passenger, PostgreSQL, Python, Red Hat Linux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SAN, Systems Administration, Ubuntu, VMware, Vignette, Virtualisation, Windows, Windows Server